ANCA SIMON

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

JAVASCRIPT, REACT, C#, .NET CORE, T-SQL

ANCARSIMON@GMAIL.COM

https://github.com/ancasimon

https://asimonbio.web.app

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anca-simon/



TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2020-2021

Non-profit organization providing intensive accelerated software development programs, teaching full-stack software development fundamentals, teamwork, and problem-solving Technologies: API; ASP.NET; Axios; Bootstrap; C#; CSS; ES6 Modules; Firebase; GitHub; HTML5; JavaScript; jQuery; JSON; JSX; SQL Server Management Studio; .NET Core; Postman; React; React Router; reactstrap; Saas; T-SQL

- Learned object-oriented programming fundamentals and development best practices, including single responsibility principle, DRY code, and modularization.
- Built single-page applications using React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and JSON. Used Firebase for data management, Google authentication, and deployment, employed Axios method with the Firebase Database REST API. Leveraged Bootstrap components for layout and data display. Bundled projects with Webpack, using ESLint for linting.
- Built backend applications using the Repository pattern for organization, using Postman to test the API calls, and connecting to SQL databases for data management and storage.
- Used GitHub for project planning and version control, mapped out relationships between different data collections in entity relationship diagrams (ERDs) via Lucidchart, and built wireframes for new projects using mogups.
- Successfully collaborated in teams virtually using tools such as Zoom, Google Meet, and Slack. Followed Scrum methodology during capstone projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE **BUSINESS ANALYST**

Contracted with TEKsystems for the TN Department of Human Services | 2016 Information technology and services recruiting organization

- Worked closely with business users to document workflows and business and technical requirements to transition current COBOL software application to Oracle Forms
- Provided visibility into project progress and commitments by managing project metrics, leading the implementation of Agile methodology, and acting as the Scrum Master for the development team. Used Team Foundation Server (TFS) to manage the backlog.

BUSINESS ANALYST & PRODUCT MANAGER UL Workplace Health & Safety | 2010-2016

Business unit of Underwriters Laboratories, providing software applications and elearning training to help improve the safety of workers across diverse industries

- Worked on multiple applications, including the PureSafety Learning Management System, its add-on Incident Management Module and Online Health Portal, and the Occupational Health Manager (OHM).
- Drove product strategy by working closely with customers, support, sales, marketing, solutions consultants, and the management team to define the product roadmap
- Managed the end-to-end Product Management process that spans market needs identification to product development to product launch and support
- Ensured product roadmap goals were successfully implemented by collaborating successfully with the development, QA, documentation, and engineering teams
- Planned release schedule, deliverables, goals, and milestones, using Rally, Defined technical and business requirements and maintained project documentation
- Increased new sales and customer expansions by providing support to the Sales team, helping with RFPs, conducting demos, and creating roadmap collateral

TECHNICAL WRITER

Epic Systems Corporation | 2005-2010

Healthcare software provider, offering a centralized site for a patient's information

- Enhanced user adoption of new features by using proprietary tools to provide a wide variety of user materials, including moment-of-need quick start guides, release notes, user guides, online help, design specifications, and test scripts
- Led a reporting data warehouse initiative to provide users more actionable reporting on clinical and billing data. Contributed to a major revamp of the online help system.
- Helped customers become successful users of the software applications and newly released features by leading customer training sessions on using documentation deliverables and by providing onsite go-live assistance

ABOUT ME

One of the most vivid memories in my BA experience is the demo where we saw the first iteration of a project I had owned from discovery and market research through mockups, requirements, and now development. Seeing an actual program where before there had been just words on paper (well, on screen) was amazing! Today, I am a developer because of that moment. I love solving technical and business problems and helping users leverage technology to enhance results.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School: Full-Stack Developer Middle Tennessee State University: MA English Lipscomb University: BA English

PROJECTS @ NSS

GEARUP

GearUp eliminates the stress of packing for outdoor adventures! A single-page React application with CRUD functionality, using Firebase, it allows you to manage your camping gear and trips. Users can create records for their gear, edit, and delete them as well as filter the gear list. They can create and edit trips and quickly put together packing lists for each trip.

Technologies: Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, Firebase, FreeLogoDesign, GitHub, Google login authentication, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSX, Lucidchart, moment.js, moqups, React, React Router, reactstrap, REST API, Sass, sweetalert2, Webpack

FOODIES UNITE

For the gourmet traveler, Foodies Unite provides meal recommendations for locations around the US and the world. It is a single-page web app with CRUD functionality, using Firebase. I used Bootstrap for the layout, FontAwesome icons for more visually appealing button icons, and JavaScript and jQuery for the program. Users can create and edit boards as well as add multiple cards to each board with details about the dining recommendation.

Technologies: Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, ESLint, Firebase, GitHub, Google login authentication, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, JSONLint, Lucidchart, moment.js, mogups, REST API, Sass, Webpack